STEVEN MEIERS

Los Angeles, CA 90064

Phone: (424) 440-5645 | Email: stevenmlmeiers@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/SMLM42 | Portfolio: www.stevenmlmeiers.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/steven-meiers/

SUMMARY

A full-stack developer who uses a background in tutoring and extensive world traveling to build a more user-friendly experience on the web. Fascinated by programming problems and enjoys overcoming the myriad challenges the field affords. Motivated problem solver who works well in groups or alone. Excited to find a challenging position in the coding and web development field.

TECHNICAL SKILLS.

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ES5, ES6, ¡Query

Frameworks: Express, Node, React

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase

Browser-Based Technologies: LocalStorage, Cookies

PROJECTS

Signed | https://github.com/luvkylo/signed | https://luvkylo.github.io/signed/

- Signed is a Web-based application that was created for the A&R team at Nettwerk Music Group to find global unsigned artists using Spotify Top 50 playlists.
- Responsibilities for this project: designing the overall layout, building the tables, and allowing sorting of the tables by any column.
- Tools Used: Spotify API, Geonames API, Firebase, D3 Visualization Tools

eeatz | https://github.com/taydougherty/eeatz | https://sheltered-mesa-77161.herokuapp.com/

- eeatz is a restaurant management software for family-owned multi-restaurant chains that allows owners and managers to access their budgets and expenses across restaurants.
- Responsibilities for this project: designing and implementing the entirety of the budget and expense history section.
- Tools Used: Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Google Charts, D3 Visualization Tools.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Private Tutor

2013-Present, LA, CA

- Worked one-on-one to help ADHD students learn and utilize proper study habits.
- Employed time management skills to help multiple students in one day, especially during hectic times such as finals week.
- Went above and beyond for students by meeting with teachers on their behalf.

Volunteer Tutor, School on Wheels Charity

2009-2010, LA, CA

- Tutored homeless children at shelters where they lived.
- These children moved often, could be 2 or more grades below their age level, and needed educational and motivational help, both of which I endeavored to provide.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate

UCLA Extension

2019, LA, CA

Completed Coursework towards History Degree

Santa Monica College

2012-2015, Santa Monica, CA

Completed Coursework towards Sociology Degree

UC Santa Cruz

2010-2012, Santa Cruz, CA

(If interested, non-job related personal information is available at www.stevenmlmeiers.com)